<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Personal Website on Mike Belov</title>
    <link>https://belovm96.github.io/myportfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Personal Website on Mike Belov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://belovm96.github.io/myportfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Caption Generation with encoder-decoder neural nets</title>
      <link>https://belovm96.github.io/myportfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belovm96.github.io/myportfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>In this group research project, I built a CNN+LSTM neural network and experimented with two variations of encoder-decoder models - Merge and Inject.
Our models were trained on a 90,000 example subset of Google&amp;rsquo;s Conceptual Captions dataset on Google Cloud&amp;rsquo;s VM.
Some of the models&amp;rsquo; metrics approach state-of-the-art results for the task of image captioning, reaching BLEU-4, METEOR and ROUGE-1 scores of 0.13, 0.14 and 0.2, respectively.
Check out this project&amp;rsquo;s github repository with a complete project report here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam Detection with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://belovm96.github.io/myportfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belovm96.github.io/myportfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>This time I wanted to explore Enron1 dataset containing spam and non-spam emails and do some Machine Learning modeling for spam detection.
Overall, most of the trained models achieved impressive classification results detecting spam &amp;gt;90% of the time with Support Vector Machine being the most optimal model out of the four built on this dataset.
Please click here to take a look at some of the visualizations from my EDA &amp;amp; classifiers&amp;rsquo; performance metrics analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning for Music Genre Recognition</title>
      <link>https://belovm96.github.io/myportfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belovm96.github.io/myportfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Being a bit of a music nerd, I decided to tackle the problem of music genre recognition using deep learning.
The key idea was to train a Convolutional Neural Network model on the visual representations of the audio signal (e.g. spectrograms) extracted from the tracks in GTZAN &amp;amp; FMA datasets.
I was able to achieve 70% accuracy classifying 10 music genres on a relatively small dataset, which was exciting and definitely worth the effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://belovm96.github.io/myportfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://belovm96.github.io/myportfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on these social media platforms:
   Platform URL     LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mike-belov-610911140/   GitHub: https://github.com/belovm96   Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100008388225655    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>